华森公馆
The Waltham residence.
你好  是艾蜜莉的父母家吗
Hi! Is this Emily's parents' house?
我是管家
This is the housekeeper speaking.
顺带提醒下  小姐
And, by the way, young lady,
讲电话不能这样没礼貌
that is not how one addresses a person on the telephone.
你要先表明自己的身份
First one identifies oneself
再请你想找的人过来
and then asks for the person with whom one wishes to speak.
我是菲比·布菲
This is Phoebe Buffay.
我是想麻烦你
I was wondering, please,
如果不是很麻烦的话
if it's not too much trouble, please,
我能有机会和艾蜜莉·华森小姐通话吗
might I speak with Miss Emily Waltham, please?
华森小姐去排练餐会了
Miss Waltham is at the rehearsal dinner.
嘲弄别人是不礼貌的  再见
And it is not polite to make fun of people. Goodbye.
不  我会有礼貌  我发誓
No, no! I'll be nice, I swear.
可以把现场的电话给我吗
Could you just give me the number for where they are?
我恐怕没有权利泄露这项讯息
I'm afraid I'm not at liberty to divulge that information.
有人正要去破坏婚礼  明白吗
Somebody is on their way to ruin the wedding, okay?
我得提醒一下他们
And I have to warn somebody.
你不给我号码  我就一路杀过去
So if you don't give me that number, I'm gonna come over there
把你一脚端到新格劳肯郡去
and I'm gonna kick your snooty ass all the way to New Gloukenshire!
喂  喂
Hello? Hello?
她知道我会狠狠教育她的
She knew I could kick her ass.
-乖儿子  -妈  爸
- Hi, sweetheart. - Mom, Dad.
抱歉迟到了
Sorry we're late.
是我不好  我坚持要坐"管子"
My fault. I insisted on riding the tube.
茱蒂  孩子都在
Judy, the kids!
杰克  那是英国人对地铁的俗称
Jack, that's what they call the subway.
-我以为  -爸  我们懂
- I thought... - Dad, we got it.
我爸和继母来了
Here comes my dad and stepmom.
盖勒先生  盖勒夫人
Mr. And Mrs. Geller.
-这是史蒂芬  -你好  亲爱的
- This is Steven... - Hello, darling.
和安瑞亚·华森
...and Andrea Waltham.
幸会
Very nice to meet you.
亲爱的  是盖勒一家
Darling, the Gellers.
亲爱的  是亲家
Darling, it's the Gellers.
她只想着自己  我不该娶她的
She's very self-involved. I should never have married her.
抱歉  你说什么
Sorry, what?
-是盖勒一家  -在哪里
- It's the Gellers. - Where?
那边一个  那边一个
That's one and that's another one.
很高兴认识你们
Lovely to meet you.
谢谢你们出一半的钱
Nice of you to offer to pay for half the wedding.
不客气  管他什么习俗呢
Oh, forget it. The hell with tradition.
我们很乐意
We're happy to do it.
我们知道结个婚有多花钱
We know how expensive weddings can be.
而且我家以后可能就没机会办婚礼了
Besides, this may be the only wedding we get to throw.
这笑话在全世界都好笑呢
A joke that's funny in all countries.
先生
Sir?
里面有什么
What's in it?
羊酪  水田芥和意大利咸肉
Goat cheese, watercress and pancetta.
那根本不是吃的呀
That's not food.
英国的一切都不一样  我想回家
Everything's different here. I want to go home.
我想念我的家人  想念咖啡馆
I miss my family, the coffeehouse.
我连菲比的长相都不记得了
I can't even remember what Phoebe looks like!
我们才来了三天
It's been three days.
你只是有点想家了
Okay, you're just a little homesick.
放轻松  好好玩就对了
Would you just try to relax and just enjoy yourself?
你也变了
You're different here too.
在英国的你好刻薄
You're mean in England!
搞什么
What the hell?
-怎么了 爸  -什么事
- What's up, Dad? - What's the matter?
我这一半的婚礼帐单太扯了
This bill for my half of the wedding. It's insane.
怎么会这么贵  请客是在她家里的
How can it be so much? The receptions are at their house.
花  酒  一楼重铺地毯
Flowers, liquor. Re-carpet first floor?
新的客用浴室  园林设计
New guest bath, landscaping.
我这是在出钱给他家重新装修啊
I'm paying to remodel this guy's house.
我要把那个混蛋臭骂一顿
I'm gonna give that son of a bitch a piece of my mind.
爸  别激动  求你了
Relax, dad. Please.
今晚我不想让艾蜜莉因为任何事情不开心
I don't want anything to upset Emily tonight.
她这两天已经够心烦了
She's had a hard enough couple of days as it is.
给我  我去跟他谈
Here. Here. Let me go talk to him.
告诉他谁也别想占盖勒家的便宜
You tell him no one takes advantage of the Gellers.
杰克  有时候我都忘了你多有气概了
Jack. Sometimes I forget how powerful you can be.
我要去喝个烂醉
And I'm gonna go get drunk.
-你好  -你好
- Hello. - Hello.
下一班飞伦敦的班机什么时候
When is your next flight to London?
半小时后有一班
There's one leaving in 30 minutes.
还剩一个空位
And I do have one seat left.
谢谢  谢谢  谢谢
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
临时票的价钱是2700块
The last-minute fare on this ticket is $2700.
我的信用卡额度不够
I just don't think I have enough left on my credit card.
你可以分两张刷
You can split it with another credit card.
好  那五张可以吗
Okay. How about five?
谢谢
Thank you.
我需要你出示一下护照
I'm just going to need to see your passport.
好吧  我这会儿没带
Okay, you know what? I don't have it,
但我能告诉你它在我床头柜上的具体位置
but I can tell you exactly where it is on my nightstand.
这样吧  我有驾照
You know what? I have my driver's license.
还有一张20元钞票
And I have a 20.
说真的  我爸不会付室内烧烤架的钱
Face it. My father is not going to pay for the built-in barbecue.
还有  别扯了  凉亭也免谈
And believe me, you can kiss your gazebo goodbye.
我或许可以争取到新草皮
I might be able to get you the new lawn.
那也得给草坪的装饰品
Then you have to give us the lawn ornaments.
我要是答应  会被我爸笑死
I go back there with lawn ornaments, he'll laugh in my face.
你说句话好吗  史蒂芬
Will you say something, Steven?
别对我这么说话
Don't take that tone with me.
好吧  随你
All right, you can.
嗨  菲比
Hi, Phoebs.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God!
你改变心意了
You changed your mind.
你现在或许想一个人静一静
I know you probably want to be alone,
你现在不想说这事儿
you don't want to talk about it.
没关系  我就是想告诉你
That's fine. I just want you to know,
你这么做是对的
I think you're doing the right thing.
拜拜  菲比
Bye, Phoebs!
等下  你要去哪里
Wait. Where are you going?
你又想干什么  等等
What are you doing? No, wait.
为什么每次她这么做的时候我都在怀孕
Why am I always pregnant when she does that?
好
Okay.
我跟罗斯认识很久了
I've known Ross for a long time.
他和他第一任女朋友交往我都知道
In fact, I know him when he was going out with his first girlfriend.
我以为他们相处得很顺利
I thought things were going to work out for him,
直到那天他把女朋友给吹爆了
until the day he over-inflated her.
天呐
Oh, dear God!
华森府邸
Hello, Waltham Interiors.
华森太太
Mrs. Waltham.
我想找罗斯的伴郎之一
I need to speak with either one of the best men
或是他妹妹莫妮卡
or Ross' sister, Monica.
-你是谁  -我是菲比·布菲
- Who is this? - Oh, I'm Phoebe Buffay.
罗斯最要好的朋友之一
I'm one of Ross' best friends.
既然你是罗斯的好朋友
If you're one of Ross' best friends,
怎么没来参加婚礼
why aren't you here?
因为我不能坐飞机  我怀了我弟的孩子
Yeah, 'cause I can't fly. I'm having my brother's babies.
这是广播台在做节目吧
Am I on the radio?
不是
No.
我可以找他们吗  我有非常非常要紧的事
Can I talk to one of them? It's very, very important.
你无聊死我了  我要挂了
I'm bored of you now. I'm going to cut you off.
我相信我们都很高兴
I'm sure we're all very excited
罗斯和艾蜜莉要在蒙哥马利礼堂结婚
that Ross and Emily are getting married at Montgomery Hall.
我朋友要在蒙提大厅结婚
To think, my friend getting married in Monty Hall.
拜托  蒙帝·霍尔啊
Come on, Monty Hall!
"大家来挑战"主持人啊  笑一下吧
Let's Make a Deal. Come on, you people!
算了  恭喜罗斯和艾蜜莉
All right, forget it. Congratulations to Ross and Emily.
伴郎二号  乔伊.崔比安尼
Best man number two, Joey Tribbiani.
我没钱德勒那么会说笑话
I'm not good with the jokes like Chandler here.
我只想说恭喜这对幸福的新人
I just want to say congratulations to the happy couple.
我在我家附近咖啡馆认识罗斯
I first met Ross in this coffeehouse back home.
家
Home.
纽约市
New York City.
在那里大家都认识我
Where everybody knows my name.
总之
Anyway...
我爱你们
I love you guys.
但是我更爱美国
But not as much as I love America.
我们马上回家好不好
Can we please go home now?
你要回去了
Are you going home?
我正想进一步了解你
I was hoping to get to know you better.
我哪儿也不去了  美人
I'm not going anywhere, sweetheart.
我有笑啊
I was laughing.
有笑出声吗
Out loud?
我不想让别人觉得我很白痴
I didn't want everyone to think I was stupid.
你这几天怎么样
So how are you doing?
我妈快把我逼疯了
My mother's driving me crazy.
但罗斯结婚了  我真的很高兴
But Ross is getting married. I'm happy.
我不会让任何人扫我的兴
I'm not going to let anything spoil that.
我只想说罗斯真是个好青年
I just want to say that Ross is a wonderful young man.
谢谢  我们都喜欢他
Thanks. We like him.
天呐  你生他时一定才十几岁
My God! You must have been a teenager when you had him.
我绝对不会付钱
There's no way in hell I'm paying for it.
听着  我只问一件事
Look, we're down to just one point.
能不能婚礼后再解决
Could we please, maybe just settle it after the wedding?
好吧  但我想只说
All right, fine, but I just wanna say
我是不会出钱给你们挖酒窖的
I'm not paying for your wine cellar,
你个爱占便宜的
you thieving,
小矮子  要是没有我们你们现在都得说德语
would-be-speaking-German-if-it-weren't-for-us, cheap little man!
那家伙是喝多了
The guy was hammered, okay?
你怎么可能像罗斯的妈妈
There's no way you look like Ross' mother.
-那他为什么那么说  -因为他疯了
- Then why would he say it? - Because he's crazy!
之前他还过来找我
He came up to me earlier
要感谢我在《泰坦尼克号》里的感人出演
and thanked me for my very moving performance in Titanic.
我妈说得对  我嫁不出去了
My mother's right. I'll never get married.
这么说就
You know what, that is...
谁会不想要你
Who wouldn't want you?
拜托  我是个单亲妈妈  儿子都30岁了
Please! I'm a single mom with a 30-year-old son.
我今天要结婚了
I'm getting married today!
早啊  罗斯
Morning, Ross.
-我今天要结婚了  -对啊
- I'm getting married today! - Yeah! You are.
你觉得他知道我在这儿吗
Do you think he knew I was here?
我以前没跟你做过这档事
Well, I've never done that with you before.
没
Nope.
你怎样
So how are you?
还好吗
You okay?
很好  你呢
Yeah. Yeah. You?
很好  很好
Oh, yes. Yes.
你呢
You?
刚问过你了
We did you.
-我该走了  -好  当然
- I better get going. - Yeah. Absolutely.
你能不能别看
Could you not look?
我不想看
I don't want to look.
喂
Hello?
你死哪去了
Where the hell have you been?
我昨晚在外面睡的
I spent the night out.
我认识了可爱的伴娘  她好...
I met this cute bridesmaid. She is so
我不想听
I don't want to hear about her.
菲比  我最喜欢的还是你
Pheebs, you know you're still my number-one girl.
不  出大事了  瑞秋去伦敦了
No. No. We have an emergency. Rachel's coming to London.
太好了
Great!
一点也不好
it's not great.
她要去跟罗斯表白
She's coming to tell Ross that she loves him.
但是罗斯爱艾蜜莉
But he loves Emily.
我知道
I know that!
你得阻止她  她会破坏婚礼的
You have to stop her. She's going to ruin the wedding.
好
Okay.
我该做的都做了
So I've done my part, okay?
现在该你负责  接下来没我事儿了哈
It's your responsibility now. The burden is off me.
-对吧  -对
- Right? - Right.
说说那个伴娘吧
So tell me about this girl.
你有看见莫妮卡吗
Hey, have you seen Monica?
我没有在跟莫妮卡交住
I'm not seeing Monica!
-什么  -什么
- What? - What?
我们得找到她  菲比刚跟我通了电话
We gotta find her. Phoebe just called.
瑞秋要来向罗斯表白
Rachel's coming to tell Ross she loves him.
天呐
Oh, my God!
没错  你知道莫妮卡在哪里吗
I know. That's why we gotta find Monica.
你知道她在哪儿吗
Do you know where she is?
不知道  你在逼问什么
No. What's with the third degree?
干脆拿灯照我的眼睛算了
Why not just shine a light in my eyes?
然后我意识到  我一直以来做的事
And so then I realized,all the stuff that I had been doing...
向约书亚求婚
...proposing to Joshua,
骗罗斯说我没办法参加婚礼
lying to Ross about why I couldn't come to the wedding...
都只是一种...
...was all just a way
抱歉  可以打个岔吗
I'm sorry,can I interrupt?
你真是个很差劲  很差劲的人
I just want to say that you are a horrible,horrible person.
你说什么
Pardon me?
你说你爱那个男人
You say you love this man,
却要去破坏他的大喜之日
and yet you're about to ruin the happiest day of his life.
我不得不同意你朋友菲比的话
I'm afraid I have to agree with your friend Pheebs.
这是个很糟糕  很糟糕的打算
This is a terrible,terrible plan.
但他必须知道我的感受
But he has to know how I feel.
为什么
But why?
他爱那个艾蜜莉  这么做绝对没好处
He loves this Emily person. No good can come of this.
-我觉得你错了  -才怪
-Well,I think you're wrong. -Oh,no.
顺便说一句  很显然
And by the way,it seems to be perfectly clear
你们当时是分手状态
that you were on a break.
我的天呐
Oh, my God!
跟仙境一样
It's like a fairyland.
是啊  很恐怖吧
I know. It's horrible, isn't it?
我好喜欢  希望我的婚礼也能这么美
I love it. I only hope my wedding looks this good.
-我只希望  -有些话就别接了
- I just hope... - You can let some of them go by.
注意  莫妮卡  我们开始注意瑞秋了
Listen, Monica, we really need to start looking out for Rachel.
我守前门
I'll cover the front door.
你守楼后面那个大洞
You watch that big hole at the back of the building.
罗斯那里有钱德勒顾着
And I got Chandler covering Ross.
我干嘛管钱德勒在哪里
Why would I care where Chandler is?
你知道
You know...
有的时候我根本不喜欢钱德勒
sometimes I don't even like Chandler.
好
Okay.
我愿意
I do.
-没错  第二个比较好  -是吗
- You're right. It's the second one. - Right?
乔伊
Hello, Joey.
嘿  费丽西蒂
Hey, Felicity.
我整天都在想你
I thought about you all day.
再跟我讲讲纽约的事
Talk New York to me again.
别管纽约了
Forget about it.
你好吗
How you doing?
没什么好谈的  我们不会付酒窖的钱
There's nothing to discuss. We're not paying for your wine cellar.
你们总得折中一下
You have to meet me in the middle here.
嘿  你再跟我罗唆
Hey, you keep pushing me on this,
我就把你的屁股踹得折中
my foot's gonna meet the middle of your ass.
怎么了
What's going on?
没事  一切都在掌握中
Nothing, nothing. Everything's under control.
你想尝尝厉害吗
You want a piece of me, sir?
你是这个意思吗  想尝尝我的厉害
Is that what you're saying? Want a piece of me?
够了  双方家长  退后
That's it! Parents! Parents! Back away!
今天是我们的大喜之日
This is our wedding day!
你们给我好好相处
From now on, everyone gets along.
谁再多说一个字
And if I hear one more word,
就别想抱孙子外孙  没错
no grandchildren! That's right!
-好吧  好吧  -抱歉
- Okay, okay. - Sorry, old boy.
我用大拇指就能扳倒你
I could kill you with my thumb, you know.
这是怎么回事
What was all that about?
只是一些费用上的
It was this disagreement over...
天呐  你真美
My God! You look beautiful.
婚礼前看到新娘会不吉利
You're not meant to see me before the wedding. It's bad luck.
我们的恶运应该都耗尽了
I think we've had all the bad luck we're going to have.
天呐  瑞秋
My God, Rachel!
你来了  我真不敢相信
You're here. I can't believe it.
怎么回事  你怎么跑来了
What happened? Why are you here?
我只是来
I just came to...
我只是得告诉你
I just needed to tell you...
恭喜你
congratulations.
你好  华森府邸
Hello, Waltham Interiors.
华森太大吗  又是我  菲比
Mrs. Waltham? It's Phoebe again.
求求你  求求你
Can I please, pleae,
求求你让我跟其中一位伴郎说句话吧
please talk to one of the best men?
我保证这是最后一次
This is gonna be the last time, I promise.
乔伊  有个女生找你
Joey, there's a girl on the phone for you.
真好
Great!
-你好  -乔伊  我是菲比
- Hello! - Joey, it's Phoebe.
你有拦住瑞秋吗
Did you stop Rachel?
没有  但没事
No, but it's okay.
她只是抱抱他  仅此而己
She just came in and gave him a hug. That's it.
-没有破坏吗  -没有
- Nothing got ruined? - No.
太好了
That's so great!
现在怎么样了
So, what's going on now?
我正在走红毯
I'm walking down the aisle.
还在走
Still walking.
现在我和罗斯一起站在前面
Now I'm at the front with Ross.
是菲比
It's Phoebe!
他看起来很不爽
He looks pretty mad.
我得挂了
I better go.
等一下  别挂机让我听
Wait! Hold it up so I can listen.
-昨晚的事真是  -愚蠢
- What we did last night was... - Stupid.
既疯狂又愚蠢
Totally crazy, stupid.
我们当时怎么想的啊
What were we thinking?
我晚上去找你  好吗
I'm coming over tonight though, all right?
当然好
Oh, yeah, definitely.
各位亲朋好友
Friends, family...
我们今天齐聚于此
we are gathered to celebrate here today
庆祝罗斯与艾蜜莉喜结良缘
the joyous union of Ross and Emily.
愿我们今朝的幸福
May the happiness we share today
永远与他们同在
be with them always.
艾蜜莉  跟着我念
Now, Emily, repeat after me.
-我  艾蜜莉  -我  艾蜜莉
- I, Emily... - I, Emily...
-将把罗斯  -将把罗斯
- take thee, Ross... - take thee, Ross...
作为我合法的丈夫  无论健康与否
as my lawfully wedded husband, in sickness and in health...
直到死亡把我们分开
till death parts us.
作为我合法的丈夫  无论健康与否
As my lawfully wedded husband, in sickness and in health...
直到死亡把我们分开
until death parts us.
罗斯
Now, Ross.
跟着我念
Repeat after me.
我  罗斯
I, Ross...
将把艾蜜莉
take thee, Emily...
将把瑞秋
take thee, Rachel...
艾蜜莉
Emily.
我还要继续吗
Shall I go on?